<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-16th-amendment</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1909-10-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=sixteenth+amendment</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Constitution of the United States was purposely made difficult to amend. Madison, the "Father of the Constitution," was against "innovation," and Hamilton feared the turbulent, changing people. So the Constitution was made unchangeable except by a vote of two-thirds of Congress, and three-fourths of the State Legislatures or State Conventions. 
          A minority of the voters today, if properly placed, can block any amendment. Of the four hundred and thirty-five amendments proposed from 1889 to 1904, not one was adopted. It is the belief of many people that the Constitution can never be amended.
          We, on the other hand, believe the Sixteenth Amendment permitting the income tax is possible, probable, inevitable. The resolution was unanimously adopted by the Senate, and almost unanimously by the House. Thirty-five of the forty-six States must ratify, and thirty-five States will be found. The South is for it; the West is for it; the real people of the East are for it; the two parties have declared in its favor; and President Taft has taken his stand on it. It is more than a mere question of an income tax, although that is important. It is a question of national sovereignty, of the right of ninety millions of people to tax themselves as they deem just and expedient. It is an issue upon which, in times of danger, national welfare, even national existence, might depend. The Sixteenth Amendment must and will be adopted.
          But it will not be adopted by the people staying at home and wishing for it. It must be made an issue in every State, in every assembly district. Time fights on the side of the Sixteenth Amendment. There is no limit. Once a State adopts it, the ratification lasts forever. But if the ratification is not made at the first session, it may again be proposed for the second, third, tenth, or ninety-ninth time. If we do not succeed at first, we can try, try again.
          The Sixteenth Amendment must be ratified, not only to enable our Government in times of peace and war to impose equitable taxes, but also to place the fundamental law of the land, where it should be placed, in the hands of an intelligent, tolerant, and liberty-loving people.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064469/1911-01-24/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Sixteenth Amendment in the Louisiana Legislature
          (To the Caucasian)
          As shown by the House Journal of 1910, the Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States was endorsed by the popular branch of the General Assembly as follows:
          Mr. Johnson of Washington introduced House Concurrent Resolution No. 1, ratifying the Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which was referred to the committee on Federal relations. After due consideration, this committee reported as follows:
          "House of Representatives, State of Louisiana, Baton Rouge, La., May 20, 1910. To the Honorable the Speaker and Members of the House of Representatives of the State of Louisiana: Gentlemen, I am directed by your committee on Federal relations to submit the following report: House Concurrent Resolution No. 1, by Mr. Johnson (of Washington) ratifying the Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States (here printing the resolution). Favorably.
          W. E. Richardson, Chairman.
          Two members of the committee dissented and submitted a minority substitute.
          On June 2, this substitute was indefinitely postponed on motion of Mr. Johnson of Washington by a rising vote of 68 yeas and 31 nays. The question then recurred on the motion to adopt the resolution to ratify the amendment. The roll being called resulted as follows: Yeas 78; nays 31; absent 7.
          Thus it is seen that the House voted overwhelmingly in favor of the Income Tax Amendment.
          But in the Senate—as shown by the Senate Journal, the Sixteenth or Income Tax Amendment was overwhelmingly defeated.
          On June 7, the House Concurrent Resolution by Mr. Johnson was so amended as to refer the said Sixteenth Amendment to a general State primary election for ratification or rejection by the qualified electors, said vote to be binding on the next General Assembly. The vote on this amendment was yeas 26, nays 11, absent 4.
          As amended, the Johnson resolution was concurred in by the Senate by the following vote: Yeas 28, nays 9, absent 4.
          The Johnson Concurrent Resolution having thus been materially amended by the Senate was sent back to the House for concurrence in the Senate amendment. The House refused to concur, and the amended resolution was sent to conference, both houses appointing conferees. There the Johnson resolution rests, and the Sixteenth Amendment failed of ratification in so-called Democratic Louisiana.
          On the South rests the responsibility. But the Democrats will elect a new General Assembly in 1912.
          A Legal Observer
          January 21, 1911
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020558/1912-03-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          This Resolution and Another Providing for Ratification of Income Tax Amendment Will Be Rushed Through
          There was nothing in it yesterday but unless somebody spikes the guns before 1 o'clock today, the hair-raising stunts will begin and before sundown, every judge in the state of Arizona and every man who has a few dollars and sixty cents will have license to tremble in his shoes, if he is at all nervous in his temperament. Rules have been adopted sufficient for the legal transaction of legislative business, and as soon as the decks are cleared for action this morning, a concurrent resolution will be introduced in both houses, submitting to the people an amendment to the constitution providing for the recall of judges, and it will be passed quicker than either President Taft or the proletariat can say Jack Robinson.
          Before the smoke clears away, a joint resolution will drift in, to the effect that Arizona endorses the proposed Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, providing for an income tax. Thirty-one states have already endorsed it, and only five more are needed. There will be one less today, and the time has arrived for the plutocrats to throw up their hands, or at least stand up and be counted.
          Anyhow, that was the frame-up last night.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042373/1913-02-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Marks Epoch in U.S. Tax System
          Washington, Feb. 3.—Wyoming's ratification of the Income Tax Amendment makes it one provision of the Constitution of the United States. Congress will enact a law to levy a tax probably becoming effective during the extraordinary session to be called by President Wilson in March. The tax itself in its provision and limitations is left to Congress. Congressional leaders, who have been waiting for the final ratification by the states, estimate that the income tax would bring the government about $100,000,000 a year.
          As the tax is provided by the Constitution, the proposed excise tax, framed by the Democratic leaders in 1912 to meet the Supreme Court's decision which held the former income tax unconstitutional, will be dropped. Some of its provisions may be included in the new law.
          Sixteenth Amendment
          Washington, Feb. 3.—The provision authorizing an income tax as now made part of the federal Constitution will be known as the "Sixteenth Amendment" and reads as follows:
          "Article XVI.—The Congress shall have power to lay and collect taxes on incomes, from whatever source derived, without apportionment among the states, and without regard to any census or enumeration."
          The change in the fundamental law of the land marks a new epoch in the American tax system. For the first time, Congress is given specific authority by a provision of the federal Constitution to levy an income tax. All previous efforts for a tax of this kind have been without the explicit authority of a constitutional provision. The change also marks a broad development of the economic and fiscal system of the country, providing a basis for taxation similar to the systems now in force in Great Britain, Austria, Switzerland, Spain, and various other countries.
          New Source of Revenue
          Probably the most important aspect of an income tax, as now authorized by the Constitution, is that it adds a new source of revenue for the government. At present, the two great sources of government revenue are customs duties levied by tariff acts on goods imported from foreign countries and internal revenue taxes on tobacco, spirits, oleomargarine, and certain other articles. Each of these sources at present produces a little less than half of the total revenues of the government.
          In 1911, the total government revenues were $700,100,906, and of this, customs duties yielded $313,846,269, while internal revenue taxes yielded $331,759,375. The remainder came from sales of public lands, the corporation tax, and various miscellaneous sources. Under an income tax, however, a new and far-reaching source of revenue is provided for the government, and this will in turn reduce the amounts required from the other sources of revenue, customs, and internal revenue, in order to meet the expenses of government. This last phase is likely to have an important bearing on tariff legislation as hereafter enacted.
          Before the amendment formally becomes a part of the Constitution, today's action of the legislature must be transmitted to the Secretary of State at Washington and proclamation of the ratification made.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1913-02-06/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Amendment is Ratified
          Taxing Incomes of Rich.
          Democrats Will Pass a Speedy Law to Enforce Measure.
          Washington, Feb. 5. Here is the Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, ratified Monday:
          "Article XVI. The Congress shall have power to lay and collect taxes on incomes, from whatever source derived, without apportionment among the several States, and without regard to any census or enumeration."
          Wyoming had the honor of making the amendment effective. Within two hours after word was received that the Wyoming Legislature had ratified the amendment, a telegram was received by Senator Richardson, of Delaware, stating that his State had also ratified the amendment, and to this was added New Mexico, making thirty-eight States to act favorably. Utah and New Jersey are expected to do the same. Only thirty-six were needed.
          The Democrats' tariff makers of the House and Senate forthwith announced that they would begin preparations at once to enact an income tax law as a part of the Democratic tariff program at the coming extra session of Congress. Senator Simmons, of North Carolina, who will probably be the next chairman of the Finance Committee, spoke for the Senate. Representative Hull, of Tennessee, the income tax expert of the Ways and Means Committee, spoke for the House.
          Senator Norris Brown, of Nebraska, Republican, author of the amendment, which he introduced in the Senate on June 17, 1909, with pardonable pride, announced to the Senate during the afternoon that three-fourths of the sovereign States had ratified it. He congratulated the Senate and the country on the result. The amendment will not become actually a part of the Constitution until the notice of the ratification by Wyoming or Delaware has been formally filed with the Secretary of State, which will doubtless be within a few days.
          The Democrats propose to raise approximately $100,000,000 a year by the new tax and to graduate it so that persons of great wealth will pay at a higher rate.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038161/1913-02-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Sixteenth Amendment
          The Sixteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States has been ratified by the legislatures of thirty-eight states, two more than the required three-fourths. It gives Congress the power "to lay and collect taxes on incomes, from whatever source derived, without apportionment among the several states, and without regard to any census or enumeration."
          Congress having been given this power, what is its duty? We believe that it should at once proceed to pass an income tax law. Some argue that no such duty devolves upon Congress; that the amendment simply gives Congress the power to act but that it does not follow that it should act at once, as present conditions do not demand such action and the provision is solely for the purpose of giving Congress the power to pass a law when the necessity shall arise.
          As viewed in the light of history, is this argument good? We think not. The Sixteenth Amendment is the only amendment to the Constitution in forty-three years. In 1893 Congress passed an income tax law, which the Supreme Court held unconstitutional. For this reason, those favoring an income tax law proposed amending the Constitution. Finally, in 1909, both houses of Congress by a three-fourths vote passed the proposed amendment, and now three-fourths of the states by their legislatures have ratified it.
          Since a few years after the close of the Civil War, there has been practically as much need for an income tax at one time as another. The members of Congress believed that the people wanted this law, or they never would have passed the amendment, as most of them were voting to impose a tax upon their own incomes. The members of the state legislatures that ratified it also thought that the people wanted it, or they would not have voted for it, because it is not the type of measure that is passed by a legislature against the wishes of the people.
          The people believe that an income tax is fair and just, and Congress should pass one at once. We can see no reason why one should not be passed. It is only right that the people who are receiving the largest benefits from government should pay for keeping it up; that those who can best afford to pay for maintaining the government should do so. A person's income is the best gauge of his ability to pay. An income tax, it is hoped and believed, will take some of the burden of the support and maintenance of the government off of the shoulders of the poor and put it on the shoulders of the rich, where we believe it belongs.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1915-09-25/ed-1/?sp=8&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Income Tax Law Again Attacked
          Washington, Sept. 23. Counsel for Union Pacific Railroad stockholders and others have filed a brief in the Supreme Court attacking as unconstitutional the income tax provisions of the Underwood-Simmons tariff law.
          The attorneys contend that while the Sixteenth Amendment empowers Congress to impose a tax on "incomes from whatever source derived," the framers of the law stretched it to cover many taxes other than on income.
          It is asserted, too, that there is no constitutional authority for taxing a specific class of persons, unmarried men, more than others, or for the super-tax imposed upon men with incomes over $20,000.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86061215/1915-10-14/ed-1/?sp=1&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Testing Income Tax
          Constitutionality of Law Is Put Up to the Supreme Court of the United States.
          Washington, D.C., Oct. 13.—An annual revenue to the government of $82,000,000 depends on the outcome of arguments today before the Supreme Court on the constitutionality of the income tax. The first cases to reach the court under the new system of federal taxation and the first involving the construction of the Sixteenth Amendment were at issue.
          Attacking the law were corporations objecting to the law in part and as an entirety; mining companies voicing objections to the tax on mining income; and individuals, attacking principally the additional tax on incomes in excess of $20,000. The main defense of the law has been prepared by the government.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030273/1920-03-09/ed-1/?sp=3&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Stock Dividends Held Non-Taxable
          U.S. Supreme Court Decides, 5 to 4, They Are Not Really Income
          March 8, 1920.—The Supreme Court to-day held by a 5 to 4 decision that the Federal government cannot tax stock dividends as income despite the income tax amendment to the Constitution. Sections of Article I of the Constitution prevent such taxation, it was held.
          That section of the 1916 income tax law assessing as income such dividends declared by corporations out of excess earnings since March 1, 1913, was declared by the court to be unconstitutional. Similar provisions are contained in later revenue laws and the decision can be held to eliminate these sections also.
          As a result of the decision the Government must refund millions of dollars in taxes collected on stock dividends. The amount probably will exceed $10,000,000 for the years 1917 and 1918, the Treasury Department recently informed Representative Longworth (Ohio), but because of the complicated nature of income tax returns, officials of the Bureau of Internal Revenue stated they could make no definite estimate of the amount the Government must refund.
          The decision swept aside all contentions of the Government, with the exception that the court declared if stock dividends are sold and the holder realizes a profit "such profit like any other is income, and so far as it may have arisen since the Sixteenth Amendment is taxable by Congress."
          How Justices Were Aligned.
          Five to four decisions are becoming quite prevalent in the court on decisions of vital interest to finance and business. Those who formed the majority were Chief Justice White, Associate Justices McKenna, Pitney, Van Devanter, and McReynolds. Justices Holmes and Day dissented on one ground and Justices Brandeis and Clarke on another.
          Leading Democrats who were responsible in large measure for income tax legislation were astonished at the decision, some declaring it largely nullified the income tax amendment to the Constitution.
          Representative Hull (Tenn.) said the decision gave rich corporations and stockholders an opportunity of evading taxation to a large extent and throwing the burden on poor people and made possible the evasion of hundreds of millions of taxes. With the declaration by the court that taxation of stock dividends is unconstitutional, notwithstanding the Sixteenth Amendment, Congressional leaders doubted if there was any legislative step now by which the same purpose could be effected. Likewise, it was feared that a constitutional amendment on the point might not stand.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064057/1916-01-29/ed-1/?sp=2&q=sixteeth+amendment+income+tax</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          INCOME TAX VALID, SAYS SUPREME COURT
          The Decision Was Unanimous One. Expected Levies on Great Fortunes Will Be Made, Etc.
          Washington—The income tax was declared constitutional Monday by the Supreme Court of the United States in a decision which swept aside every contention raised against it and, in the opinion of congressional leaders, opened the way for increasing the tax rate on great fortunes to help pay for national defense.
          The decision was announced by Chief Justice White and was unanimous. It came on an appeal of Frank R. Brushaber from the action of the New York federal court in refusing to enjoin the Southern Pacific, of which Brushaber was a stockholder, from paying the tax. The case raised substantially every point involved in all the five income tax suits before the court.
          One of the points involved was the provision of the income tax law allowing mining corporations to make a 5 percent deduction annually from gross income for depletion of mines. The court upheld this provision, treating it as an amendment to the old corporation tax, rather than a feature of the income tax.
          The basic error of those who attacked the constitutionality of the tax, Chief Justice White held, was in regarding the Sixteenth Amendment as a grant of new power to levy a direct tax without apportionment among the states, instead of merely as removing all occasions for apportionment of income taxes among the states. In substance, the court held that the Sixteenth Amendment had not empowered the federal government to levy a new tax but that "the whole purpose of the amendment was to relieve all income taxes from a consideration of the source whence the income was derived."
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-james-reese-europe</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024055/1909-11-20/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+James+Reese</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          MUSICAL NUMBERS
          Musical Director, James Reese Europe
          ACT I
          Opening Chorus: Company
          "The Same Old Moon is Shining": Herbert Sutton and College Boys
          "Keep on Smilin'": The Four Bills
          "Don't Tell Tales Out of School": Slim, Plunk, Minnehaha, and Truscalina
          "Pickinniny Days": Alda Overton Walker and Picks
          "Tiner, Won't You Come Out in the Moon Light": Slim and Ada Girls
          Finale: Ensemble
          ACT II

          Prelude: Mayme Butler and Company
          "Bleeding Moon": The Prophetess
          "The Big Red Shawl": Plunk and Chorus
          "On the Road to Monterey": Red Feather
          Wildfire Dance: Alda Overton Walker
          Finale: Company
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025891/1911-05-20/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Europe+James+Reese</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          New York Notes
          The Clef Club drew a record-breaking crowd to the Manhattan Casino on last Thursday night. It was estimated that between five and six thousand persons were present. It was certainly the largest gathering of colored people New York has ever witnessed. This popular musical organization is under the leadership of Mr. James Reese Europe and is composed of 50 mandolins, 10 violins, 10 pianos, 10 cellos, 25 harp guitars, 10 banjos, 2 flutes, 1 organ, 5 bass violins, 2 clarinets, 3 tympani, and a full set of the 57 of Heinze's mixed pickles.
          The program was an excellent one in every way, although another Washington boy carried off the second honors of the occasion with his beautiful composition "Porto Rico." Following is the program in full:
          Opening Medley by the full Clef Club Symphony Orchestra
          "That Long Lost Chord" - Clarence Bush and chorus
          "Way Down in Georgia" - Wm. Parquette and chorus
          "Bamboola, A Samoan Love Song" - Frederick Bryan, Clef Club Symphony Orchestra
          "Toddlin'" - The Toledo and chorus
          "The Suffragette" by the author, that quaint comedian Al Brown
          "Love's Menu" by Smyrna, directed by the composer Wm. H. Tyers, played by the Clef Club Symphony
          "Dance La Ballet Grotesque" - Henry S. Creamer
          A duet - Henry Troy and Harvey White
          "Exit" - George Cook
          "Wake Me Up, I Am Dreaming" - Henry Troy and octette
          "On Bended Knees" composed by H. T. Burleigh, played by the Clef Club Symphony Orchestra
          Song and Shoe Dance - Wm. Williams
          "Transmagnificentmandanuality" and chorus
          "Lorraine Waltzes" composed by James Reese Europe, dedicated to his mother, for the first time by the Clef Club Symphony Orchestra
          "Grizzly Bear" - Tom Bethel and orchestra
          "She's Everything and Then Some More" - F. Patrick and Henry S. Creamer
          "Lovie Joe" - Christian and chorus
          "The Separate Battalion" composed by Reese Europe, dedicated to the School Cadets of Washington, D.C., played for the first time by the Clef Club Symphony Orchestra
          Chorus "Darktown Is Out Tonight" composed by Will Marion Cook, played and sung by the entire company
          Finale: Clef Club March composed by James Reese Europe, played and sung by the company.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-05-03/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Clef+Club</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1914-06-14/ed-1/?sp=80&q=EUROPE+JAMES+REESE</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90061556/1918-03-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+James+R</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          THE 15TH NY REGIMENT BAND
          Lyons, France—The 15th New York Regiment, one of the crack units of the American army in this country, recently arrived here. No regiment ever received a greater welcome than this crack Negro regiment.
          The entire city turned out to greet it, and the officials of the city took the lead in extending the welcome.
          When the band, under the leadership of James Reese Europe, swung down the streets of Lyons, followed by the regiment, the people of this city declared that it was simply charmed and all now declare that the band is the grandest that has ever visited here.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1918-09-29/ed-1/?sp=36&q=Europe+James+R</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          To have heard 2000 women, with the colored band of the 369th United States Infatry, under Lieutenant James R. Europe, the colored composer,
          leading them, singing:
          "Gloire, O, gloire, Alleluia!
          Gloire, O, gloire, Alleluia!
          Gloire, O, gloire, Alleluia!
          Gloire, O, gloire, Alleluia!
          Car Dieu marche en avant!"
          must have been worth going 3000 miles to hear.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1919-02-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+Jim</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          All New York Joins to Pay Honor to 'Hell Fighters' in Parade on Fifth Avenue
          New York turned out by the hundreds of thousands today to welcome and to do honor to Col. William Hayward's "Hell Fighters" of the 369th United States Infantry, formerly New York's 15th colored regiment. Fifth Avenue was a jam of humanity from 23rd Street to 110th Street, along which the colored doughboys marched, and Lenox Avenue from 110th to 145th Street was a replica of its more fashionable neighbor.
          No more joyful, cheerful, or enthusiastic reception was ever accorded anywhere to heroes returning from the wars than that which took place today. The city, state, and nation joined in honoring the men who had fought their way from the Champagne to the Forest of Argonne and gave battle to and beat the best that the Boche had to offer.
          The dusky heroes themselves marched with the air of victors, heads erect, and eyes front in true soldier fashion. They marched behind Lieutenant James Reese Europe's famous jazz band, which thrilled the thousands of spectators along the curb, in shops, on steps, in windows, and on the rooftops. The music of that jazz band had proved a revelation in France, and the cheering crowds showed the same enthusiasm as the French had done.
          The parade route was lined with cheering multitudes. At every corner and every step, new cheers and shouts greeted them. White folks mingled with their colored brethren in the lower part of the avenue, but as the parade progressed uptown, the number of colored spectators grew larger.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1919-03-21/ed-1/?sp=15&q=Europe+EUROPE+JIM+Jim</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Jazz Band Created Big Stir in France
          Paris Music Lovers Ignored 'World's Masters' to Hear Plantation Melodies
          And Now Lieutenant Jim Europe Brings Them Here and Scores Encore
          Lieutenant Jim Europe is in town with his colored jazz band. The story of that band and its adventures overseas is an American epic. Here are just a few sidelights.
          One day last summer, there was a great band concert held in the Tuileries Gardens in Paris for the benefit of the families wounded by Big Bertha. Thirty thousand people paid $5 admission. The elite of the world's military musicians were there—the band of the French Republican Guard, the British Grenadiers, and the Royal Italian Band, among others. Yet the band that stole the show was Jim Europe's band of American colored boys, playing their unique jazz tunes.
          "Why people left those wonderful bands and came over to listen to us, I don't know!" Jim Europe said with a chuckle. "I thought, well, at last they've got me; they're going to knock me off my perch."
          Their opening number, "Plantation Echoes," ending with "Dixie," brought the crowd to their feet, cheering wildly. From that day on, Jim Europe's band of the 369th Infantry became the most famous band in the world.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025779/1919-05-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+James+Reese</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Colored Musicians Have Chicago Charmed
          The Associated Negro Press
          Chicago, May 8. Chicago has had a marvelous awakening during the last week, and the awakening is having a most favorable effect. On Monday night, there was an occurrence which, a year ago, would have been regarded as a pipe dream.
          Three great musical aggregations of our people, two of whom had been across the seas and thrilled the people of England and France, were playing their soul-stirring music within "gun-shot" of each other, so to speak, right down in Chicago's great "Loop" district. The first, the New York Syncopated Orchestra, under the direction of Will Marion Cook, was playing its third engagement of the season in the famous Orchestra Hall, before an audience of more than 1,000 people, with many unable to purchase seats. The second, the wonderful band of Lieutenant James Reese Europe, performed at the great Auditorium, which seats 5,000 people. The third, the band of the 365th Infantry, under Sergt. Hubert Jones, played off Michigan Boulevard, at the magnificent and spectacular Victory Arch, illuminated at night with 3,000,000 candlepower lights.
          Chicago has literally gone "music mad" over the offerings of these rare and pioneer musical aggregations. Even when the 365th band marched through the downtown streets, thousands of people followed it all the way. The audiences listening to the concerts are mixed, and the very elite of Chicago white society are ever present in boxes and other parts of the audience, where there is no discrimination in securing seats.
          "This effort, though very expensive, is having the most wonderful effect in helping our Race," said Will Marion Cook to the Associated Negro Press. "We are showing the white people that we have arrived and are capable of doing everything equally as well as any, if given an opportunity."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-05-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Europe+Jim</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Lieut. Jim Europe Stabbed to Death
          "Hell Fighters'" Band Leader Said to Have Fought With Drummer
          BOSTON, May 9.—Lieutenant James Reese (Jim) Europe died at a hospital here to-night as the result of a wound in the neck alleged to have been inflicted by Herbert Wright, a drummer in the "Hell Fighters" (369th Infantry) Band, of which Europe was leader.
          The two engaged in an altercation at Mechanics' Hall, where the band has been giving a series of concerts.
          Europe, who was standing in the wings while the band was playing a selection, called out to Wright to "put more pep in the sticks." Wright left his drum and walked hastily over to Europe, who retreated to his dressing room.
          Wright followed him, and after some words, the police allege, he drew a knife and slashed Europe in the neck. Wright was arrested.
          Lieutenant "Jim" Europe, the only officer of the old 15th Regiment, later renamed the 369th, won fame on two continents through his music. Before the war, he was an exponent of "jazz" tunes in New York, particularly well known to patrons of the Castle House and the Ziegfeld Roof.
          Europe returned to this country with his regiment on February 12 and led the music as the troopship Stockholm passed the Statue of Liberty. He marched with his regiment in the farewell review to the Negro warriors, and since then had been touring the country with the band that took jazz to the battle area.
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
