<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-16th-amendment</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1909-10-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=sixteenth+amendment</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Constitution of the United States was purposely made difficult to amend. Madison, the "Father of the Constitution," was against "innovation," and Hamilton feared the turbulent, changing people. So the Constitution was made unchangeable except by a vote of two-thirds of Congress, and three-fourths of the State Legislatures or State Conventions.

A minority of the voters today, if properly placed, can block any amendment. Of the four hundred and thirty-five amendments proposed from 1889 to 1904, not one was adopted. It is the belief of many people that the Constitution can never be amended.

We, on the other hand, believe the Sixteenth Amendment permitting the income tax is possible, probable, inevitable. The resolution was unanimously adopted by the Senate, and almost unanimously by the House. Thirty-five of the forty-six States must ratify, and thirty-five States will be found. The South is for it; the West is for it; the real people of the East are for it; the two parties have declared in its favor; and President Taft has taken his stand on it. It is more than a mere question of an income tax, although that is important. It is a question of national sovereignty, of the right of ninety millions of people to tax themselves as they deem just and expedient. It is an issue upon which, in times of danger, national welfare, even national existence, might depend. The Sixteenth Amendment must and will be adopted.

But it will not be adopted by the people staying at home and wishing for it. It must be made an issue in every State, in every assembly district. Time fights on the side of the Sixteenth Amendment. There is no limit. Once a State adopts it, the ratification lasts forever. But if the ratification is not made at the first session, it may again be proposed for the second, third, tenth, or ninety-ninth time. If we do not succeed at first, we can try, try again.

The Sixteenth Amendment must be ratified, not only to enable our Government in times of peace and war to impose equitable taxes, but also to place the fundamental law of the land, where it should be placed, in the hands of an intelligent, tolerant, and liberty-loving people.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
